Here's another way to prevent overfitting.
现在再介绍另一种防止过拟合的方法
So, let's say this is you,
假设这是你
and one day you decide to practice sports.
有一天 你决定要开始运动
So, on Monday you play tennis,
周一你打网球
on Tuesday you lift weights,
周二举重
on Wednesday you play American football,
周三玩美式橄榄球
on Thursday you play baseball,
周四打棒球
on Friday you play basketball,
周五打篮球
and on Saturday you play ping pong.
周六打乒乓球
Now, after a week you've kind of
运动一周后
noticed that you've done most of them with your dominant hand.
你似乎发现大部分运动都是惯用手在玩
So, you're developing a large muscle on that arm but not on the other arm.
所以这个手臂的肌肉很明显 但是另一条手臂却不行
This is disappointing.
这很让人失望
So, what can you do?
你可以怎么办？
Well, let's spice it up on the next week.
下周改变下策略
What we'll do is on Monday we'll tie
周一 我们将右手绑在后面
our right hand behind our back and try to play tennis with the left hand.
尝试用左手打棒球
On Tuesday, we'll tie our left hand
周二 把左手绑到后面
behind your back and try to lift weights with the right hand.
尝试用右手举重
Then on Wednesday again,
到了周三
we'll tie our right hand and play American football with the left one.
再次绑起右手 并用左手玩美式橄榄球
On Thursday we'll take it easy and play baseball with both hands, that's fine.
周四 我们缓缓 用两只手打棒球
Then, on Friday we'll tie both hands behind our back and try to play basketball.
周五 我们把两只手都绑起来 并尝试打篮球
That won't work out too well.
这样效果不太好
But it's OK. It's the training process.
但是没关系 这是训练过程
And then on Saturday again,
到了周六
we tie our left hand behind our back and play ping pong with the right.
将左手绑起来 并用右手打乒乓球
After a week, we see that we've developed both of our biceps. Pretty good job.
一周后 两只手臂的二头肌都锻炼了 很棒
This is something that happens a lot when we train neural networks.
我们训练神经网络的时候 就会经常这样
Sometimes one part of the network has
有时候网络的某个部分
very large weights and it ends up dominating all the training,
权重非常大 最终对训练起到主要作用
while another part of the network doesn't
而网络的另一部分
really play much of a role so it doesn't get trained.
并没有起到多大作用 所以没有被训练
So, what we'll do to solve this is sometimes during training,
要解决这一问题 有时候在训练中
we'll turn this part off and let the rest of the network train.
我们将这部分关掉 让网络的其他部分接受训练
More thoroughly, what we do is as we go through the epochs,
更具体的情况是 我们经历一些 epoch
we randomly turn off some of the nodes and say,
随机关闭某些节点
you shall not pass through here.
并说不要通过这里节点
In that case, the other nodes have to pick up
在这种情况下 其他节点需要承担责任
the slack and take more part in the training.
在训练中起到更大的作用
So, for example, in the first epoch we're not allowed to use this node.
例如 在第一个 epoch 中 我们不能使用这个节点
So, we do our feat forward and our back propagation passes without using it.
我们在前向反馈和反向传播时不使用这个节点
In the second epoch,
在第二个 epoch 中
we can't use these two nodes.
我们不能使用这两个节点
Again, we do our feet forward and back prop.
同样进行前向反馈和反向传播
And in the third epoch we can't use these nodes over here.
在第三个 epoch 中 我们不能使用这些节点
So, again, we do forward and back prop.
再次进行前向反馈和反向传播
And finally in last epoch,
在最后一个 epoch 中
we can't use these two nodes over here.
我们不能使用这里的两个节点
So, we continue like that.
继续这样
What we'll do to drop the nodes is we'll give the algorithm a parameter.
我们放弃这些节点的方式是给算法一个参数
This parameter is the probability that each node gets dropped at a particular epoch.
该参数就是每个节点在特定 epoch 被放弃的概率
For example, if we give it a 0.2 it means each epoch,
例如 如果设为 0.2 意味着对于每个 epoch
each node gets turned off with a probability of 20 percent.
每个节点被关闭的概率是 20%
Notice that some nodes may get turned off more than
注意 某些节点被关闭的次数可能比其他节点的要多
others and some others may never get turned off.
其他一些节点可能从来都不会被关闭
And this is OK since we're doing it over and over and over.
这是正常的 因为我们一遍一遍地重复
On average each node will get the same treatment.
平均下来 每个节点都会得到相同的处理过程
This method is called dropout and it's really
这个方法叫做 dropout
really common and useful to train neural networks.
它在神经网络训练中非常常见和实用